let questions = [ 
    {
        num: 1, 
        question: "Which attribute is used to specify multiple alternative sources for an image?",
        answer:"B. srcset",
        options:[
            "A. alt",
            "B. srcset",
            "C. multiple",
            "D. media"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 2, 
        question: "Which attribute is used to define a keyboard shortcut for an element?",
        answer:"C. accesskey",
        options:[
            "A. shortcut",
            "B. accelerator",
            "C. accesskey",
            "D. keyshort"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 3, 
        question: "Which HTML5 attribute is used to specify that the input field must be filled out before submitting a form?",
        answer:"A. required",
        options:[
            "A. required",
            "B. validate",
            "C. mandatory",
            "D. validate-required"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 4, 
        question: "Which CSS property is used to create an animated transition effect between different property values?",
        answer:"A. transition",
        options:[
            "A. transition",
            "B. transform",
            "C. animation",
            "D. opacity"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 5, 
        question: "Which CSS selector has the highest specificity",
        answer:"B. ID selector",
        options:[
            "A. Class selector",
            "B. ID selector",
            "C. Attribute selector",
            "D. Universal selector"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 6, 
        question: "Which CSS property is used to control the stacking order of elements on a webpage?",
        answer:"A. z-index",
        options:[
            "A. z-index",
            "B. position",
            "C. float",
            "D. display"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 7, 
        question: "What is a closure in JavaScript?",
        answer:"B. A function that has access to variables from its outer function scope even after the outer function has returned.",
        options:[
            "A. A built-in object in JavaScript used for data encapsulation.",
            "B. A function that has access to variables from its outer function scope even after the outer function has returned.",
            "C. A JavaScript file that contains reusable code.",
            "D. A way to create private variables in JavaScript."
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 8, 
        question: "What is the difference between the '==' and '===' operators in JavaScript?",
        answer:"B. '==' compares values, while '===' compares values and types.",
        options:[
            "A. '==' compares values and types, while '===' only compares values.",
            "B. '==' compares values, while '===' compares values and types.",
            "C. '==' performs type coercion, while '===' does not perform type coercion.",
            "D. '==' is used for strict equality, while '===' is used for loose equality."
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 9, 
        question: "What is the purpose of using the \"use strict\" directive at the beginning of a JavaScript file or a function?",
        answer:"A. It enforces stricter error handling and helps prevent common coding mistakes.",
        options:[
            "A. It enforces stricter error handling and helps prevent common coding mistakes.",
            "B. It enables the use of modern JavaScript features and syntax.",
            "C. It restricts the usage of global variables within the script.",
            "D. It allows the use of strict mode for debugging purposes."
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 10, 
        question: "What is the difference between \"undefined\" and \"null\" in JavaScript?",
        answer:"B. \"undefined\" means a variable has been declared but has not been assigned a value, while \"null\" is an assigned value that represents no value or no object.",
        options:[
            "A. \"undefined\" is a primitive value, while \"null\" is an object.",
            "B. \"undefined\" means a variable has been declared but has not been assigned a value, while \"null\" is an assigned value that represents no value or no object.",
            "C. \"undefined\" is a global object, while \"null\" is a local object.",
            "D. \"undefined\" is used to define null values, while \"null\" is used for undefined values."
        ]
    }
];
